Kyler Bomhof

Full-Stack Software Developer

616.405.0409

kdbomhof@gmail.com

kylerbomhof.com

Grand Rapids, MI

EXPERIENCE

kylerbomhof.com

07/2023 - Present

A custom mobile-centric website that highlights my skills, experience, and projects. Developed using Next.js, styled with Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI. Currently hosted on Vercel.

typetest-cli

06/2023 - Present

A lightweight type speed tester for the terminal, written in Python. Published on PyPI and easily installable using pip on any machine capable of running Python.

Software Developer Intern

Auto-Owners Insurance

05/2023 - Present

As a software developer, I primarily built full-stack applications to reduce labor-intensive maintenance tasks by agents.

I followed the Scrum framework while collaborating with a team of business analysts, quality assurance engineers, and other software developers.

I was personally responsible for front-end and back-end architectural decisions, as well as their implementation. I mainly utilized React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Jest, and SQL Server.

Information Technology Intern

Haworth

05/2022 - 05/2023

I worked with members of the Information Security team to roll out new security software to over 7,000 devices.

I wrote and deployed scripts using Microsoft Endpoint, Azure AD, and Configuration Manager.

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Michigan Technological University Bachelor of Science - B.Sc

Aug 2020 - Dec. 2023

- 3.65 GPA
- IT Oxygen team lead, managing machine learning projects
- · Member of University Innovation Fellows

SUMMARY

Software developer who is passionate about the software he writes, and systems he architects. A personal advocate for keeping code testable, and actually tested.

Kyler has professional experience with full-stack development, working as a team, and utilizing the Scrum framework.

SKILLS

Testing

TypeScript/JavaScript	Advanced
React.js	Advanced
Node.js	Advanced
Python	Expert
Go	Intermediate
Docker	Intermediate
Jenkins	Intermediate
Tailwind CSS	Advanced
CSS/SCSS	Intermediate
Material UI	Intermediate
HTML5	Advanced
Bash	Advanced
Linux	Advanced
Git	Expert
SQL	Intermediate
SQL Server	Intermediate
Lua	Intermediate
Ruby	Intermediate
Java	Intermediate
С	Advanced
C++	Intermediate
Vim	Advanced